A Finding Aid to the William Christenberry papers, circa 1917-2018, bulk 1979-2018, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Recorded Materials, 1980-2009; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 4 Linear feet Box 4-7; 14.23 Gigabytes ER04-ER12
  - William A. Christenberry, Jr.: A Portrait (1997), Staniski, Stanley J., 1993-1997; 8.1; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Box 4-5
    This series includes sound and video recordings and one digital video recording compiled during the creation of William A. Christenberry, Jr.: A Portrait (1997). The material includes footage of Christenberry, his home state of Alabama, interviews, lectures and talks, his studio, and artwork.
    - William A. Christenberry, Jr.: A Portrait, film by S.J.. Staniski (1997), Digital Video Recording, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 3.15 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER04)
    - Tape 1-4, Christenberry, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key; 4 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Tape 5, DC-Alabama; Tape 6, Christenberry, 1995 August 13; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Tape 7, Christenberry; Tape 8, Christenberry Home, 1995 August 14; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Tape 9-10, Christenberry, 1995 August 14; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Tape 11-12, 1995, undated; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Tape 13-14, Christenberry, 1995 August 15; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Tape 15-16, Christenberry, 1995 August 15-16; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Tape 17-18, Christenberry, 1995 August 16; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Tape 19, Christenberry, Stewart Cemetery; Tape 20, Stewart Cemetery, Interview, 1995 August 16; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Tape 21, Christenberry; Tape 22, Klan Room Studio, 1995 August-September; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Tape 23, Klan Art Studio, Flat and Dolls; Tape 24, Klan Art Studio, 1995 September 25; 1995 October 4; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Tape 25-26, Christenberry, 1995 October 18; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Tape 27, Christenberry; Tape 28, Duke University, 1995 October 18; 1995 November 21; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Tape 29, Stills; Tape 30, "Christenberry: The Early Years," Morris, 1996 January 12, undated; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Tape 31-32, Morris Museum Interview, 1996 January 12-13; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Tape 33, Morris Museum; Tape 34, Dining-room Interview, 1996 January 13; 1996 January 24; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Tape 35, Interview, Dining Room, etc.; Tape 36, D.C. Studio Construction, 1996 January 24; 1995 January 29; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Tape 37, Painting Warehouse; Tape 38, Empty Klan Room, 1996 February 19; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Tape 39-45, Museum II, 1996 August 8-10; Archival Resource Key; 7 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 5, Folder 7-10)
    - Tape 46-47, Art, Transparencies, 1997 January 8, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - Christenberry, #1-2, 1995 August 13; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (Hi8) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Documentary Audio Tapes, 1997; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Interview, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (Hi8) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Place I Know, Visions of the South (2003), 2000-2003; 8.2; Archival Resource Key; .7 Linear feet Box 6
    Found here are video and digital video recordings related to The Place I Know, Visions of the South (2003). The tapes include footage of Christenberry on the road, a family reunion, and other scenes from Christenberry's trips to Alabama.
    - The Place I Know, Visions of the South, film by S.J. Staniski (2003), Digital Video Recording, Archival Resource Key; 0.86 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER05)
    - Roll #1, Family Reunion, 2000 July 15; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP); 1 Videocassettes (MiniDV) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Roll #2-5, Family Reunion, Boom, Bill, 2000 July 15; Archival Resource Key; 4 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
    - Roll #6, Alabama GV's; Roll #7, Alabama GV's, Mrs. Christenberry, Boom, 2000 July 16; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Roll #8, Mrs. and Mr. Christenberry; Bill, 2000 July 16; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Roll #9, Bill on the Road, Bill and Sambo; Roll #10, Bill on the Road, Christenberry Homestead, 2000 July 17; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Roll #11, Bill on the Road, Christenberry Homestead, Cemetery, Boom, Wire, 2000 July 17; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Roll #12, Cemetery, Smith House, Boom, Wire; Roll #13, Smith House, Boom, Wire, 2000 July 18; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Other Recorded Materials, 1995-2009, undated; 8.3; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Box 6-7
    Found here are video and digital video recordings from Christenberry's studio, homemade movies, lectures and interviews, and a couple of other third-party films Christenberry was involved in. Also found are some audio and digital audio recordings of interviews and lectures.
    - War Klan Room, 1995 September 15; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Christenberry Dinner, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Christenberry Dinner, 2000 August; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (MiniDV) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Morris Museum Gallery Talk; J. Richard Gruber, 1996 January 14; Archival Resource Key; 3 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
    - Alabama Dream, 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Boxes and Desk; Bill Flipping Pages and Tool Box, 2000; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Family; Still Photos, 2000; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Interview; Artwork B-roll, 2000; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Christenberry On Book of Polaroids by Walker Evans, radio program Studio 360, WNYC New York, NY (2002), Digital Audio Recording, Archival Resource Key; 0.589 Gigabytes Eight computer files (Folder ER06)
    - Documenting the Face of America: Roy Stryker and the FSA/OWI Photographers, film by Jeanine Isabel Butler (2007), Digital Video Recording, Archival Resource Key; 3.19 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER07)
    - Southern Graphics Council International Convention Opening (2005 March 31), Digital Video Recording, Archival Resource Key; 0.468 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER08)
    - A Conversation with Bill Christenberry and Robert Lehrman at the Hemphill Gallery, 2005 May 7; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Interview with Kurt Anderson, Studio 360, 2006 August 31; Archival Resource Key; 1 Electronic discs (DVD); Transfer not possible. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Radio Interviews: All Things Considered, NPR (2006 August 3), Studio 360, WNYC (2006 September 3), Digital Audio Recordings, Archival Resource Key; 0.321 Gigabytes Four computer files (Folder ER09)
    - Christenberry Lecture at Hammer Museum, 2006, 2008; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER10 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Christenberry Lecture at Hammer Museum, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA (2006), Digital Audio Recordings, Archival Resource Key; 0.887 Gigabytes Two computer files (Folder ER10)
    - Christenberry Lecture at Washington and Lee University, Lexington, VA (2009 March 11), Digital Video Recording, Archival Resource Key; 3.27 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER11)
    - Christenberry, Hemphill Fine Arts, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Electronic discs (CD); Transfer not possible. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - "A House of Many Memories"; Christenberry Music, undated; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER12 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "A House of Many Memories", film by J.S. Staniski (2000), Digital Video Recording, Archival Resource Key; 1.49 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER12)
    - "A Sound Portrait of William Faulkner," National Public Radio, 1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (MiniDV) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Unidentified, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 7, Folder 20)